Take your time.
There's no rush.
We made it.
We finally made it.
Here.
Who was that?
Hey, look. Look.
It's so beautiful!
Amazing.
It's a nice place, isn't it, Satoru?
The air is crisp here.
Can I have all the kids
gather around me?
We'll go over a few precautions.
-Sorry, Satoru, I'll be right back.
-Okay.
Okay, everyone gather up!
Watch your step.
Be careful!
First, we'll be getting ready
for the barbeque.
When you are using a knife,
please make sure you do it
around an adult staff member.
After the barbeque is finished,
we'll gather trash into groups,
and bring them to this area.
-Everybody understand?
-Yes!
Nice answer!
Okay, let's make this a fun and safe
camping experience.
Oh, thank you.
Mom?
Something the matter?
Mr. Yashiro was one of the volunteers.
I'm obviously just joking!
Kumi, cut the green peppers.
-Okay.
-Can you do it?
-Yeah, Kumi can do it.
-Really?
Really.
-That's really good.
-Is that all right?
SLEEPING PILLS
It tastes so good eating outside!
This is my first barbeque
since grade school.
Yeah, of course it is.
You've been asleep since then!
-Here's some meat.
-That looks so good!
And they're doing fireworks tonight.
Really? Seems like they planned a lot.
There's a stamp rally event
after this, too.
They said you get a prize if you win!
Satoru, we're getting first place, got it?
Kumi, fill up your canteen before you go.
Okay!
I'll go do that now.
What's this?
You can do it, Satoru!
Got the stamp!
The hint for the next stamp location
is a happy musician
beyond the swaying ground?
Swaying ground...
A boat?
Let's look at the map.
Oh, I figured it out!
The swaying ground is the rope bridge!
And here's the happy musician!
Why?
Because tanukis
beat their tummies like a drum.
All right! Well, let's go, Satoru!
I knew this was the swaying ground.
I was right!
Kumi, don't sway it so much.
Oh, sorry.
It's so scary!
Are you okay, Satoru?
You can do it, Satoru!
Yeah.
We're almost to the second one.
Got the second one!
The next one is...
I got it!
Could we take a short break?
You're still not 100 percent yet, huh?
I bet the fireworks would look beautiful
from here. It's perfect!
-What did you say, Kumi?
-Nothing.
Anyway, come on, Satoru,
let's go to the next one already.
Let's go.
-Welcome back!
Let's see, it looks like you
and Mr. Fujinuma finished 12th.
Good job.
-Good job!
-Welcome back.
-Good work.
You guys finished 13th.
-Good job.
-Welcome back.
Oh, welcome back, Kumi!
We didn't win because Satoru
was too slow!
I'm sorry to hear that.
Oh, hey, Satoru.
Could I borrow your watch?
I guess I forgot my phone,
and I don't know what time it is.
Oh, okay.
Oh, it's already four o'clock?
I need to get dinner ready.
I'm going to go help prepare
for the fireworks.
What about you, Satoru?
I'm getting a quick checkup,
then taking a break.
Well, hurry up. There'll be a line
for dinner if you're late.
Okay, I will.
Okay, Satoru.
I'll see you for the fireworks.
You know...
you seem pretty happy
even though you didn't win.
I guess I should probably
tell you at least.
I wouldn't want to cause any worry.
Hello, Kenya? I just stepped away from
Kumi. I'll be on my own for a while.
Okay, I'll keep an eye on her from here.
I don't want Yashiro to know
we're onto him.
So, make sure he doesn't spot you.
Okay, I will.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I remember now.
All of it.
All of it?
Even the one who did everything to you?
Yes.
I can wait if you need some time
to process it all.
Gaku Yashiro.
Our teacher,
Mr. Yashiro.
Now he goes by the name Manabu Nishizono.
He's a councilman
for the city where you live.
So, it was him.
You suspected Yashiro was the killer?
I'm impressed.
What I noticed was the model of the car
that fell in the lake.
The police knew it was the same model
as Yashiro's car,
but they ultimately concluded
it was immaterial.
But I couldn't let it go.
And I knew what you were doing.
That's when I started to look into it.
I'm going to go to this camp with Kumi.
SASANQUA GET-TOGETHER
This,
"Economic Planning Committee Chairman,"
is Yashiro. It's a trap, Satoru.
You can't go, it's too dangerous.
I see. Yashiro is probably planning
to kill Kumi there
and frame you for the crime.
Kenya.
Let's turn his trap
into an opportunity.
-Satoru, you're not thinking of--
-I'm not planning on getting revenge.
This time, I will get him arrested,
and have him admit his crimes.
Yashiro will probably target Kumi,
like you said.
If we can stop him,
I think we'll be able to gather
enough evidence to put him away.
I'm in, Satoru.
It's our fate...
to put an end to Yashiro.
We'll guard Kumi care--
No.
I want Kumi to enjoy herself
and have a good time.
But, Satoru...
It's her first big trip since her surgery,
and I want to give her a chance
to make new friends.
Because having friends
is something special.
We'll make sure Kumi has a good time
while we stop Yashiro's plan.
If we can do that, then we win.
Okay.
Kids!
We're going to start preparing
for the fireworks!
Everyone, please gather around!
-Okay, I'm going now, Sachiko.
-Okay.
Please bring a blue sheet and a
folding chair from the admin building.
It's over here.
Here it is.
Here.
-Here.
It's almost time.
LET'S GO PICK SATORU UP.
COME TO BUNGALOW F AT 4:30. - SACHIKO
I knew he'd use this tactic.
THIS IS SATORU. WAIT AT YOUR PLACE.
I'M ON MY WAY.
Airi.
This is Li'l P.
-Cute, right?
-Kumi.
Could we trade phones
just while we're at the campsite?
What?
It has all the numbers you'll need,
like your home and my mom's.
I don't really get why,
but it's fine with me.
-Here.
Kenya, Yashiro just messaged Kumi
to come to a bungalow.
I'm going to try to lure him elsewhere
by mail.
Keep watch for me.
This will ruin Yashiro's plan.
Maybe he'll get desperate
and make a mistake.
You did it again, Satoru.
He must have his memories back.
This is it. This is the feeling.
This is what it feels like to be alive.
What a wonder this is, Satoru!
Now.
It's time for the next round.
Ready? One, two...
Is everybody ready?
Yes!
Okay, great.
Let's bring everyone here, then.
Okay! Everyone follow me!
Please follow her, kids!
Okay?
Satoru?
Kumi is heading your way
with the other kids.
Hey, you said he asked Kumi
to come to a bungalow?
I'll go check it out.
He might have left some evidence behind.
It's Bungalow F.
Just be careful.
I came to check up on you
because you're late.
Sorry, I was taking a little break.
But, you know,
you've really built up your stamina.
I'm relieved to see how much
you were able to walk.
You always watch over me like that,
don't you?
Oh, I said it aloud.
Don't say that!
It's embarrassing.
Kumi should be here to pick me up soon.
I need to get back to the field.
You'll be able to watch
the fireworks with us, won't you?
What are you talking about?
You asked Kumi to watch the fireworks
from somewhere else.
What?
Kumi told me.
Satoru gave me a letter saying we should
watch the fireworks with the musician.
I found it inside my backpack.
LET'S WATCH THE FIREWORKS TOGETHER WITH
THE MUSICIAN PAST THE SWAYING GROUND.
IT'LL BE OUR LITTLE SECRET! - SATORU
I just love secrets and surprises!
They're so exciting!
When did you learn to be so smooth?
So, who is this musician?
Musician?
-And here's the happy musician!
-Why?
Because tanukis
beat their tummies like a drum.
So scary!
I bet the fireworks
would look beautiful from here.
It's perfect!
What did you say, Kumi?
Nothing.
What's wrong, Satoru?
I completely forgot something!
I need to go!
Am I close?
I guess it's a little further.
I don't remember it being this far.
NEBARA ROPE BRIDGE
There's this troublesome thing out there
that easily disregards all the hard work
and analysis we do as doctors.
Do you know what that is?
No.
Human will.
Human will?
I don't need a reason to save a friend.
Next time, I'm going to stop it.
Don't worry, we promise we'll protect you.
I didn't give up on this
halfway through, so here we are.
Satoru? Are you okay?
Thank goodness.
It seems that I got to her
a little sooner.
Mr. Sawada!
I got a message from Kenya.
I was really worried.
Don't worry,
I don't think Yashiro is onto us.
Hey, do you have the letter
I wrote with you now?
I do.
Here.
LET'S WATCH THE FIREWORKS TOGETHER WITH
THE MUSICIAN PAST THE SWAYING GROUND.
IT'LL BE OUR LITTLE SECRET! - SATORU
You've found a crack, Satoru.
Yes.
INBOX - SACHIKO FUJINUMA
SACHIKO FUJINUMA: I'LL BE WAITING FOR YOU
AT THE SWAYING GROUND.
Yashiro has realized
that I have Kumi's cell phone.
Which means this text is for me.
He is waiting for me.
All that's left is to make
Yashiro admit to his crimes.
Subtitle translation by
Zensho Yamamoto